

Compassionate school counselor with 7+ years of positive direction of students' emotional and academic needs. Active advocate on behalf of students facing bullying. Initiated anti-bullying workshops for students and webinar on bullying for school district parents.

Professional Experience

Middle School Counselor

Overland Park Junior High. Overland Park, MO August 2017 — Present

- Coordinate educational assessment strategies leading to appropriate placement of students
- Assist with implementation of Individualized Education Plans (IEP) and Student Study Teams {SST}
- Provide both individual and group counseling services to accommodate the needs of students identified as struggling with bullying
- Coo rd i n ate se rvi ces to m eet the d evelop men ta I a n d remed i a I needs of studen ts identified with learning disabilities, including Down Syndrome, sensory integration disabilities, and spectrum disabilities
- Collaborate with school psychologist, teachers, and other school resources to meet student needs
- ♦ Communicate and work with parents cooperatively

Anti-Bullying Specialist/Counselor

YMCA, Kansas City, MO August 2014 — June 2017

- Implemented program focusing on anti-bullying including conflict resolution, character education, self-esteem, and peer mediation
- Communicated with local school administrators and counselors to update and involve them regarding activities
- Coached educators in best practices to protect at-risk students and intervene where appropriate
- Presented at local schools to educate students about the dangers of bullying and quide them through acquisition of the skills to become responsible ad vocates

Kansas City, M0 64030 yo u remai I @exa m p I e.com (452) 999-2209

Education

B.A. Psychology

Rockhurst University, Kansas City, MO September 2008-May 2012

M.A., School Counseling Program Southeast Missouri State University, Cape Girardeau, MQ August 2012-May 2014

Key Skills

- Emphasizing family-community-school relationships to end bullying
- Counseling based on student needs
- Presentation
- Learning strategies
- Teaching self-management and autonomy skills
- Social skill coaching
- Career planning
- Encouraging students to achieve academic success and fulfilling their potential
- I d entity system ic ba rri e rs d e ter ri ng equitable access

Certifications

- Missouri Initial School Counseling Certification 2019
- American School Counselor
 Association Certification IASCA)
 2019
- Missouri Licensed Professional Counselor 2014